{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Despite his best efforts to conceal his anger ......", "opta": "we could detect that he was very happy", "optb": "he failed to give us an impression of his agony", "optc": "he succeeded in camouflaging his emotions", "optd": "he could succeed in doing it easily", "opte": "people came to know that he was annoyed", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Even if it rains I shall come means ......", "opta": "if I come it will not rain", "optb": "if it rains I shall not come", "optc": "I will certainly come whether it rains or not", "optd": "whenever there is rain I shall come", "opte": "I am less likely to come if it rains", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "His appearance is unsmiling but ......", "opta": "his heart is full of compassion for others", "optb": "he looks very serious on most occasions", "optc": "people are afraid of him", "optd": "he is uncompromising on matters of task performance", "opte": "he is full of jealousy towards his colleagues", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She never visits any zoo because she is strong opponent of the idea of ......", "opta": "setting the animals free into forest", "optb": "feeding the animals while others are watching", "optc": "watching the animals in their natural abode", "optd": "going out of the house on a holiday", "opte": "holding the animals in captivity for our joy", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I felt somewhat more relaxed ......", "opta": "but tense as compared to earlier", "optb": "and tense as compared to earlier", "optc": "as there was already no tension at all", "optd": "and tension-free as compared to earlier", "opte": "because the worry had already captured by mind", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is not easy to remain tranquil when those around you ......", "opta": "behave in a socially acceptable manner", "optb": "exhibit pleasant mannerism", "optc": "are losing their heads", "optd": "agree to whatever you say", "opte": "exhibit generous and magnanimous gestures", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"The food in this hotel is no match to what were forced at late hours in Hotel Kohinoor \" means ......", "opta": "The food in this hotel is quite good compared to what we ate at kohinoor", "optb": "Hotel kohinoor served us good quality food than what we get here", "optc": "Both hotels have maintained good quality of food", "optd": "Both hotels serve poor quality of food", "opte": "it is better to eat food than remain hungry", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Although initial investigations pointed towards him ......", "opta": "the preceding events corroborated his involvement in the crime", "optb": "the additional information confirmed his guilt", "optc": "the subsequent events established that he was guilt", "optd": "the subsequent events proved that he was innocent", "opte": "he gave an open confession of his crime", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The weather outside was extremely pleasant and hence we decided to ......", "opta": "utilise our time in watching the television", "optb": "refrain from going out for a morning walk", "optc": "enjoy a morning ride in the open", "optd": "employ this rare opportunity for writing letters", "opte": "remain seated in our rooms in the bungalow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"It is an uphill task but you will have to do it\" means ......", "opta": "The work is above the hill and you will have to do it", "optb": "It is a very easy task but you must do it", "optc": "It is very difficult task but you have to do it", "optd": "This work is not reserved for you but you will have to do it", "opte": "It is almost impossible for others but you can do it", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\" You are thinking very highly about Ravi but he is not so\" means ......", "opta": "Ravi is as good as you think about him", "optb": "You have a good opinion about Ravi but he is not as good as you think", "optc": "Your view about Ravi is philosophical, keep it up", "optd": "Ravi is much better, than what you think of him", "opte": "You have a good opinion about Ravi but he does not have a good opinion about you", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"Anand stuck up a friendship with Mahesh in just 2 days\" means ......", "opta": "Anand friendship with Mahesh came to an end recently", "optb": "Anand found out the other friends of Mahesh", "optc": "Anand fixed a deal with Mahesh in 2 days", "optd": "Anand's friendship with Mahesh lasted for 2 years", "opte": "Anand became a friend of Mahesh in less than 2 days", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Although, he is reputed for making very candid statements ......", "opta": "his today speech was not fairly audible", "optb": "his promises had always been realistic", "optc": "his speech was very interesting", "optd": "people follow whatever he instructs to them", "opte": "his today's statements were very ambiguous", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The manager would like you to help Dhiraj, means ......", "opta": "the manager would like you if you help Dhiraj", "optb": "the manager desires you to help Dhiraj", "optc": "the manager likes you because you help Dhiraj", "optd": "Dhiraj expects the manager to tell you to help him", "opte": "it will be a help to the manager if you like Dhiraj", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Owing to the acute power shortage, the people of our locality have decided to ......", "opta": "dispense with other non-conventional energy sources", "optb": "resort to abundant use of electricity for illumination", "optc": "off-switch the electrical appliance while not in use", "optd": "explore other avenues for utilising the excess power", "opte": "resort to use of electricity only when it is inevitable", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He has no money now ......", "opta": "although he was very poor once", "optb": "as he has given up all his wealth", "optc": "because he was very rich once", "optd": "because he has received huge donation", "opte": "because he was very greedy about wealth", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He is so lazy that he ......", "opta": "cannot depend on others for getting his work done", "optb": "cannot delay the schedule of completing the work", "optc": "can seldom complete his work on time", "optd": "dislike to postpone the work that he undertakes to do", "opte": "always help others to complete their work", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dinesh is as stupid as he is lazy means ......", "opta": "Dinesh is stupid because he is lazy", "optb": "Dinesh is lazy because he is stupid", "optc": "Dinesh is either stupid or lazy", "optd": "Dinesh is hardly stupid but he is lazy", "opte": "Dinesh is equally stupid and lazy", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Practically, very little work could be completed in the last week as it was ......", "opta": "full of working days", "optb": "a very hectic week", "optc": "full of holidays", "optd": "a very busy week", "opte": "loaded with work", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because he believes in democratic principles, he always ......", "opta": "decides all the matters himself", "optb": "listen to others views and enforces his own", "optc": "shown respect to others opinions if they match his own", "optd": "reconciles with the majority views and gives us his own", "opte": "imposes his own views on others", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With great efforts his son succeeded in convincing him not to donate his entire wealth to an orphanage ......", "opta": "and lead the life of a wealthy merchant", "optb": "but to a home for the forsaken children", "optc": "and make an orphan of himself", "optd": "as the orphanage needed a lot of donations", "opte": "as the orphanage had been set up by him", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The employer appeared to be in such an affable mood that Rohit ......", "opta": "decided to ask for a raise in his salary", "optb": "was scared to talk to him about his leave", "optc": "felt very guilty for his inadvertent slip", "optd": "promised him that he would not commit mistake again", "opte": "was pained to press his demand for a new flat.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He always stammers in public meetings, but his today's speech ......", "opta": "was fairly audible to everyone present in the hall", "optb": "was not received satisfactorily", "optc": "could not be understood properly", "optd": "was not liked by the audience", "opte": "was free from that defect", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Even though it is very large house, ......", "opta": "there is a lot of space available in it for children", "optb": "there is hardly any space available for children", "optc": "there is no dearth of space for children", "optd": "the servants take a long time to clean it", "opte": "the municipal taxes on it are very happy", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was an extremely pleasant surprise for the hutment-dweller when the Government officials told him that ......", "opta": "he had to vacate hutment which he had been unauthorisedly occupying", "optb": "he had been gifted with a furnished apartment in a multi-storeyed  building", "optc": "he would be arrested for wrongfully encroaching on the pavement outside his dwelling", "optd": "they would not accede to his request", "opte": "they had received the orders from the court to take possession of all his belongings", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to help the company attain its goal of enhancing profit, all the employees ......", "opta": "urged the management to grant paid leave", "optb": "appealed the management to implement new welfare schemes", "optc": "voluntarily offered to work overtime with lucrative compensation", "optd": "voluntarily offered to render additional services in lieu of nothing", "opte": "decided to enhance production at the cost of quality of the product", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"Whatever Dev uttered was without rhyme or reason\" means ......", "opta": "Dev could not recite any poem or speech", "optb": "Dev said something which has no meaning, it was totally baseless", "optc": "Dev was talking something which was beyond our experience", "optd": "Dev spoke flatly without any emotion or reason", "opte": "Dev did not refer to any poem to support his statements", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He tames animals because he ......", "opta": "is fond of them", "optb": "hates them", "optc": "is afraid of them", "optd": "want to set them free", "opte": "seldom loves them", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mahesh need not have purchased the bag, means ......", "opta": "it was not necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag but he has purchased it", "optb": "it was necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag and he has not purchased it", "optc": "it was not necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag and he has not purchased it", "optd": "it was necessary for Mahesh to purchase the bag but he has not purchased it", "opte": "Mahesh already has a bag but still he purchased another one", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to raise company's profit, the employees ......", "opta": "demanded two additional increments", "optb": "decided to go on paid holidays", "optc": "requested the management to implement new welfare schemes", "optd": "offered to work overtime without any compensation", "opte": "decided to raise the cost of raw material", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The officer who had neglected to files his income tax returns had to ......", "opta": "return the files", "optb": "pay a fine", "optc": "be rewarded", "optd": "play mischief", "opte": "give warning", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Unless you work harder you will fail, means ......", "opta": "if you fail you will work harder", "optb": "you must at least plan well than you will not fail", "optc": "hardly you will fail if you do not desire so", "optd": "if you do not put more efforts, then you will fail", "opte": "if you only work and work alone, you will fail", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "His behaviour is so unpredictable that he ......", "opta": "never depends upon others for getting his work done", "optb": "is seldom trusted by others", "optc": "always finds it difficult to keep his word", "optd": "always insists on getting the work completed on time", "opte": "seldom trusts others as far as the work schedule is concerned", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}